Guide to the General Subjects Photography Collection
California Historical Society
General Subjects Photography collection,
1850s-1980s
(Bulk 1870s-1970s)
PC-GS: Box [number]
Various
94 boxes, 12 oversize boxes (ca. 23,150 images)
California Historical Society, North Baker Library San Francisco, California 94105-4014
Contains photographs and picture postcards depicting scenes of California places, people, activities, and cultural resources from the 1850s to the 1980s.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Consult repository
Scope and Contents Note
Contains photographs and picture postcards depicting scenes of California places, people, activities, and cultural resources, mainly from the 1870s to the 1980s. Each listing represents a file containing from one to more than fifty images. Some files may also include a small number of non-photographic reproductions and prints depicting images from as early as the 1770s.
Includes images depicting California's agricultural economy (crops, livestock, ranching, etc.), industry (fishing, lumbering, etc.), and mining operations, as well as common plants (cactus, redwoods, etc.) and animals (bear, coyote, etc.). Images of the California missions provide the earliest views in the collection. Other scenes of the California landscape reflect the wide variety of the state's natural features (lakes, mountains, rivers, waterfalls, etc.), and the built environment as evidenced through architecture (commercial, domestic, and public) and transportation (automotive, rail, water, etc.), and depicted in the art of individual artists. Also includes images of people engaged in community and cultural activities as members of organizations (Freemasons, Sierra Club, etc.), or participating in recreation (amusement parks, cycling, dance, swimming, etc.), theater, and social groups (Chinese, Hispanic Americans, Italians, hippies, women, etc.). The largest segment of the collection concerns the work of California photographers (chiefly portraits). These have been divided by the city in which they chiefly worked, and described in further detail as individual catalog records. Images included here compliment those found in the California Counties Photography Collection.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by subject.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Agricultural laborers--California--Pictorial works; Grape industry--California--Photographs; Redwoods--Humboldt County--Photographs; Missions--California--Photographs; Orchards--California--Pictorial works; Chinese--California--Pictorial works
Genres and Forms of Material
Photographic prints; Landscape photographs; Photographic postcards
Container List
GENERAL SUBJECTS
- Agriculture
  - General
  - Crops
    - Almonds
    - Apples
    - Apricots
    - Beans
    - Celery
    - Century Plants
    - Cherries
    - Cotton
    - Figs
    - Grapefruit
    - Grapes
    - Guayule
    - Hay
    - Hemp
    - Hops
    - Lemons
    - Olives
    - Onions
    - Oranges--#1,2
    - Peaches
    - Pears
    - Persimmons
    - Plums
    - Prunes
    - Pumpkins
    - Raisins
    - Strawberries
    - Sugar Beets
    - Wheat
    - Miscellaneous
  - Exhibitions
  - Food Processing
    - #1,2
    - Butchers and Butchering
  - Irrigation--#1,2,3
  - Labor
    - Migrant
  - Livestock
    - Blacksmith Industry
    - Burros
    - Cattle
    - Cattle--Dairy Industry
    - Chickens
    - Diseases
    - Ducks
    - Goats
    - Horses
    - Ostriches
    - Oxen
    - Pigs
    - Sheep
    - Turkeys
  - Machinery
    - Windmills
  - Ranching
    - Cowboys
      - (1850-1859)
      - (1860-1869)
      - (1870-1879)
      - (1880-1889)
      - (1890-1899)
      - (1900-1909)
      - (1910-1919)
      - (1920-1929)
      - (1930-present)
    - Cowgirls
- Alcoholic Beverage Industry
  - (1880-1899)
  - (1900-1919)
  - (1920-present)
  - Prohibition
- Animals
  - Apes
    - Chimpanzees
    - Monkeys
    - Orangutans
  - Bears
  - Birds
    - General
    - Penguins
    - Pigeons
    - Quail
    - Sea Gulls
  - Buffalo
  - Camels
  - Cats
  - Chipmunks
  - Coyotes
  - Deer
  - Dogs
    - General
    - Guide
    - Huskies
    - Police Dogs
  - Dolphins
  - Fish
    - General
    - Sharks
  - Foxes
  - Giraffes
  - Insects
    - Bees
    - Butterflies
  - Lions
  - Lynx
  - Mules
  - Porpoises
  - Prairie Dogs
  - Prehistoric
  - Rabbits
  - Raccoons
  - Reptiles
    - Alligators
    - Snakes
    - Turtles
  - Sea Lions
  - Sea Otters
  - Seals
  - Sheep, Wild
  - Tigers
  - Whales
- Archeology
- Architecture
  - Adobe
  - Architects
  - Commercial
    - Barber Shops
    - Cigar Stores
    - Hotels
    - Interior
    - Markets
    - Saloons (Unidentified)
    - Miscellaneous
  - Domestic
    - (1870-1879)
    - (1880-1889)
    - (1890-1899)
    - (1900-1909)
    - (1950-1959)
    - (1960-1969)
    - (1970-1979)
    - Undated
    - Hearst, George (Washington, D. C.)
    - Hearst, William R. (St. Donats Castle, Wales)
    - Interior
      - (1880-1889)
      - (1890-1899)
      - (1900-1909)
      - (1910-1919)
      - (1940-1949)
      - (1950-1959)
      - (1960-1969)
      - Undated
    - Iron Houses
    - Log Cabins
  - Public
    - General
    - Churches
    - Lighthouses
    - Schools (see: GS--Schools)
- Art
  - General
  - Aitken, Robert Ingersoll
  - Alden, James
  - Baumgras, P.
  - Benton, Mrs. Mary F.
  - Bierstadt, Albert
  - Bosqui, Edward
  - Boyle, Gertrude
  - Brooks, Samuel Marden
  - Brown, Grafton T.
  - Burgess, Hubert
  - Bush, Norton
  - Carlsen, Emile
  - Cartoons
    - General
    - Jump, Edward
    - Political
  - Cooper, Astly, D.M.
  - Coulter, William A.
  - Cravath, Ruth
  - Cronbach, Robert
  - Drummond, Frank V.
  - Eastman, Harrison--#1,2,3
  - Edouart, Alexander (1818-1892)
  - Fitler, W.C.
  - Gay, George H.
  - Hagerup, N.
  - Hahn, William
  - Hencke, A.I.
  - Heynsen-Jahn, Helma
  - Hill, Andrew P.
  - Hill, Thomas
  - Hilton, W.H.
  - Hittell, Carlos J.
  - Holdredge, R.G.
  - Howard, Robert
  - Hudson, Grace
  - Ihlefeld, Henry
  - Keith, William
  - Keller, A.I.
  - Lawson, P.S.
  - Lydston, William
  - Massey, Ralph
  - Mathews, Arthur F.
  - McComas, Francis
  - McLean, Richard
  - McMurtie, William Birch
  - Milsk, Mark E.
  - Moran, Thomas
  - Mullgardt, Louis
  - Nahl, Charles
  - Narjot, Ernest Etienne de Franchville
  - Notman, W.
  - Oakes, A.T. (Mrs.)
  - Otis, George Demont
  - Patigian, Haig
  - Phillips, Werner
  - Point, Nicholas
  - Posters
    - General
    - Commercial
    - Political
  - Putnam, Arthur
  - Raschen, Henry
  - Remington, Frederick
  - Rix, Julian
  - Robinson, Charles Dorman
  - Rodin, Auguste
  - Rogers, C.A.
  - Rogers, John
  - Rosenthal, Toby
  - Schenck, A.
  - Schilling, Alexander
  - Schwartz, Leah
  - Spiel, George
  - Stackpole, Ralph
  - Tavenier, Jules
  - Tojetti, Domenico
  - Turnbull, B.C.
  - Vischer, Edward (1808-1878)
  - Walker, James
  - Walter, Edgar
  - Welch, Thaddeus
  - Williams, Virgil M.
  - Wilson, Charles T.
  - Wores, Theodore
  - Yelland, Raymond Dabb
- Botany
  - General
  - Cactus
  - Flowers
    - General and Unidentified
    - Poppy, California
  - Gooseberries
  - Plants and Shrubs
  - Trees
    - General
    - Redwoods
- California
  - General
  - Republic
- Ceremonies
  - General
  - Anniversaries
  - Christenings
  - First Communion
  - Funerals
  - Graduations
  - Weddings
    - General
    - (1880-1889)
    - (1890-1899)
    - (1900-1909)
    - (1910-1919)
    - (1920-1929)
    - (1930-1939)
    - (1940-1949)
    - (1950-1959)
    - (1960-1969)
- Children
  - Boys
  - Girls
  - Miscellaneous
- Civil Disorders
  - 1894
- Communications
  - Satellite
  - Telegraph
  - Telephone
  - Television
- Costume
  - General--#1,2
  - Children
  - Men
    - General
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
    - (1850-1899)
    - (1900-1949)
    - (1950-1971)
  - Women
    - General
      - Large Photos--#1,2
      - Small Photos
    - (1850-1899)
    - (1900-1909)
    - (1910-1919)
    - (1920-1929)
    - (1930-1939)
    - (1940-1949)
    - (1950-1959)
    - (1960-1969)
    - (1970-1979)
- Crime
  - Assault
  - Drug Abuse
  - Lynching
  - Murder
  - Prisons
  - Prostitution
  - Robbery
- Currency
- Disabled
  - General
  - Blind
- Drake Plate (Sir Francis Drake)
- Ecology
  - Smog
  - Solar Energy
- Engineering
  - Aqueducts
  - Bridges
  - Surveying
- Epidemics
  - Influenza (1918-1919)
- Fire
- Furniture
- Holidays
  - Admission Day
  - Christmas
    - (1850-1859)
    - (1870-1879)
    - (1880-1889)
    - (1890-1899)
    - (1900-1909)
    - (1910-1920)
    - (1960-1969)
  - Easter
  - Fourth of July
  - Halloween
  - Labor Day
  - May Day
  - New Year's
    - (1850-1859)
    - (1880-1889)
    - (1900-1909)
    - (1910-1919)
    - (1960-1969)
  - St. Patrick's Day
  - Valentine's Day
- Industry
  - Construction
  - Dredging
  - Fishing
    - General
    - Crabs
    - Oysters
  - Garments
  - Lumbering--#1,2,3,4,5,6,7
  - Oil--#1,2,3
  - Paper
  - Printing
  - Salt
  - Steel
  - Textile
  - Whaling
- Labor
  - Strikes
    - General
    - Grape Pickers (1969)
    - National Farm Workers Association (1966)
  - Unions--Industrial Workers of the World
- Machinery
- Maps
- Medicine
  - General
  - Dentistry
  - Flu Epidemic (see: GS--Epidemics--Influenza (1918-1919))
  - Nursing
- Mining
  - General
    - Methods
  - Dredges--Gold
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos--#1,2
  - Gold Rush
    - Cartoons, Caricatures, etc.
    - Methods
    - Miscellaneous
  - Hydraulic (1854-1884)
  - Machinery--#1,2
  - Miscellaneous
- Missions
  - General
    - Post card books
  - San Buenaventura--(Ventura-1782)
  - San Carlos Borromeo "Carmel"--(Monterey-1770)
    - Large Photos--#1,2
    - Small Photos--#1,2,3
  - La Purisima Concepcion--(Santa Barbara-1787)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - Nuestra Seora de la Soledad--(Monterey-1791)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - San Antonio de Padua--(Monterey-1771)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos--#1,2
  - San Diego de Alcala--(San Diego-1769)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos--#1,2
  - San Fernando Rey de Espaa--(Los Angeles-1797)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - San Francisco de Asis "Dolores"--(San Francisco-1776)
    - Large Photos--#1,2,3
    - Post Cards--#1,2
    - Small Photos--#1,2
  - San Francisco Solano de Sonoma--(Sonoma-1823)
  - San Gabriel Archangel--(Los Angeles-1771)
    - Large Photos--#1,2
    - Small Photos--#1,2,3
  - San Jose de Guadalupe--(Alameda-1797)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - San Juan Bautista--(San Benito-1797)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos--#1,2
  - San Juan Capistrano--(Orange-1776)
    - Large Photos--#1,2
    - Post Cards --#1,2
    - Small Photos--#1,2,3
  - San Luis Obispo de Tolosa--(San Luis Obispo-1772)
    - Large Photos--#1,2
    - Small Photos
  - San Luis Rey de Francia--(San Diego-1798)
    - Asistencia de San Antonio de Pala--(San Diego-1818)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - San Miguel Arcangel--(San Luis Obispo-1797)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - San Rafael Arcangel--(Marin-1817)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - San Pascual
  - Asistencia de San Antonio de Pala (San Diego-1816)
  - Santa Barbara--(Santa Barbara-1782)
    - Large Photos--#1,2,3
    - Post Cards--#1,2
    - Small Photos--#1,2,3
  - Santa Clara de Asis--(Santa Clara-1777)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - Santa Cruz--(Santa Cruz-1791)
  - Santa Ines--(Santa Barbara-1804)
    - Large Photos
    - Small Photos
  - Unidentified
- Monuments
- Motion Picture Industry
  - General
  - (1920-1939)
  - (1940-1949)
  - (1950-1954)
  - (1955-1959)
  - (1960-1969)
  - (1970-present)
  - Pornography
- Music
  - General
  - Light Opera
  - Opera--#1,2
- Natural Disasters
  - General
  - Earthquakes
  - Fires
  - Floods
- Natural Features
  - Beaches--Unidentified
  - Lakes
    - Angora
    - Bear
    - Eleanor
    - Lake of the Woods
    - Mary
    - Mono--Post Cards
    - Nellie
    - Round
    - Sardine
    - Smith
    - Tahoe--#1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8 (Also see: Counties--(El Dorado)--Lake Tahoe)
    - Unidentified
  - Mountains
    - General
    - Black Buttes
    - Castle Crags
    - Mount Hood
    - San Bernardino (Mountains)
    - Shasta (Mount)--#1,2,3,4
    - Tallac (Mount)
    - Whitney (Mount)
  - Oceans
  - Parks
    - General
    - Grand Canyon--(Arizona)
    - Kings Canyon National Park (see: CO--(Fresno)--Kings Canyon National Park)
    - Lassen Volcanic National Park
      - General
      - Cinder Cone
      - Lake Tartarus
      - Lassen Peak
        - General
        - Eruptions
    - Yellowstone National Park
    - Yosemite National Park
      - General Views--#1,2,3,4,5,6
      - Campers and Tourists--#1,2,3
      - Creeks
      - Lakes/Rivers--General
      - Lakes
        - Mirror
        - Tenaya
      - Mountains
        - General
        - Cathedral Spires
        - Eagle Point
        - El Capitan
        - Glacier Point
        - Half Dome
        - Liberty Cap
        - North Dome
        - Sentinel Rock
        - Table Mountain
        - Three Brothers
        - Washington Column
        - Watkins
      - Rivers
        - Cascades
        - Happy Isles
        - Merced
      - Waterfalls
        - Bridal Veil Falls
        - Nevada Falls
        - Vernal Falls
        - Yosemite Falls
          - Large Photos
          - Small Photos
        - Waterfalls--Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous
  - Rivers
    - General
    - American River
    - Cosumnes River
    - Eel River
    - Feather River
    - Kern River
    - Mokelumne
    - Russian River
    - Sacramento River
    - Stanislaus River
    - Truckee RIver
    - Tuolumne River
    - Yuba River
  - Snow (Snow Scenes)
  - Trees
  - Water
  - Waterfalls
    - General
    - Mossbrae Falls
    - Rainbow Falls (Colorado)
- Organizations
  - General
  - American Legion
  - American Nazi Party
  - American Red Cross
  - Boy Scouts of America
  - Boys Club of America
  - California National Guard
  - California Naval Militia
  - Daughters of the American Revolution
  - Democratic Party
  - E Clampus Vitus (Clampers)
  - Freemasons
    - General
    - Scottish Rite
    - Shriners
  - Grand Army of the Republic
  - Knights of Pythias
  - Ku Klux Klan
  - Native Daughters of the Golden West
  - Native Sons of the Golden West
  - Odd Fellows, Independent Order of
  - Red Men, Improved Order of-Degree of Pocahontas-Tahoe Council, #99
  - Republican Party
  - Salvation Army
  - Sierra Club
  - Socialist Party
  - Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (SPCA)
  - Synanon
  - United Crusade
  - Volunteers of America
- Photographers
  - Alameda
    - Ball, George
  - Bakersfield
    - Aston, Frank C.
    - Nelson, Christopher A.
  - Berkeley
    - Hilcox Photo Co.
    - Waters, Raper James
  - Chico
    - Alworth, N.B.
    - Brinkerhoff, A.E.
    - Tuttle, William Nutting
  - Colusa
    - Boysen, Iwer
    - Valleau, George W.
  - Eureka
    - Altpeter
    - Anderson, Hugh
    - Eayers
    - ChaseCo.
    - Dowe, Oscar S.
    - Flaglor, Amasa P.
    - Freeman, Emma B.
    - Gatliff
    - GatliffThompson
    - Holmes, Alex
    - MillerChase
    - Perrott, C.E.
    - ShawLambert
    - Strong, Nathan B.
    - Tollman
    - TuttleJohnson (William Nutting Tuttle)
    - Van Burkleo, Leroy
    - Vansant, Joshua Jr.
    - Wunderlich, J.P.
  - Eureka (Nev.)
    - Monaco
  - Fort Jones
    - Heller, Louis
  - Fresno
    - Higgins, E.R.
    - Rifenburg Dowe (A.G. Rifenberg)
  - Gold Hill (Nev.)
    - Waters, Raper James
  - Healdsburg
    - Downing, Jos. H.
    - Maxwell, Darrow Co.
  - Jackson
    - Kay, Wallace
  - Los Angeles
    - Bertrand
    - Davidson, L.S.
    - Dewey, George N.
    - Garden City Foto Company
    - L.Kohler
    - Lamson Studio (Joseph H. Lamson)
    - Marceau, Theodore C.
    - Parker Co.
    - Putnam Valentine
    - Schumacher, Frank G.
    - Steckel, George
    - Steckel Lamson
    - Sunbeam Art Studio
    - Westervelt, James D.
    - Wolfenstein, Valentin
  - Merced
    - Medina, F.
  - Napa
    - Bacon Bros. (Frank W. and J. Ed)
    - Brayton, J.G.
    - Strong, Mark Hopkins
  - Oakland
    - Belle-Oudry, E.
    - Bushnell, Frederick H.
    - Dames, William W.
    - Dames Arrowsmith
    - Dorsez, Fernando H.
    - Dunham, Allen Murray
    - Harkness, F.M.
    - Haussler, Frederick O.
    - Ingersoll, William B.
    - Kipps, Alfred K.
    - Ormsby, Elon D.
    - Scharz Studio
    - Schramm
    - Strong, J.D.
    - Webster, F.A.
  - Oroville
    - Hogan
    - Kusel, Edward Abraham
  - Palo Alto
    - Hansen
  - Pasadena
    - Kohler, E.F.
  - Petaluma
    - Johnson, B.R.
    - Reed
    - Ross, George
    - Ross Ormsby
    - Wayne
  - Placerville
    - Baker, Ellis William
    - Gilbert, George H.
  - Redding
    - Valentine
  - Sacramento
    - Bailey, A.P.
    - Baldwin, John E.D.
    - Beals, Henry Sherman
    - Boysen
    - Briggs, William
    - Dickman, William
    - Esterle, Albert Mack
    - Gregory, A.O.
    - Hodson, Burton M.
    - Hodson, John R.
    - Leftwich (John Warwich or Mary F.)
    - Reed, William L. (Reed Company)
    - Sherriff, Thomas B.
    - Smith, Alfred L.
    - Todd, John A.
    - Varney, A.K.
    - Walters, N., Walters Co.
    - Wolfe, Samuel A., Wolfe Kildare
    - Young, Conrad
  - San Bernardino
    - Shaffner
  - San Diego
    - Lenz, J.M.
    - Mitchell
    - Sherriff, John A.
  - San Francisco
    - Abell Priest
    - Acme Photographic Studio (Sarah Fletcher)
    - Adams, Ansel (See: Restricted Materials--Adams, Ansel)
    - Addis Koch (Robert W. and John)
    - Anderson, Hugh
    - Armer, Laura Adams--#1,2,3,4,5,6,7
    - Aydelotte [1906 Earthquake Views]
    - Bailey Photograph Gallery
    - Baker, E.W.
    - Bayley, Wilbur Fisk
    - Bayley, W.F. N.J
    - Bayley Cramer's Fine Art Gallery
    - Bayley Winter (Wilbur Fisk and Robert)
    - Bayley's Photograph Gallery
    - Blauert Widder (Frederick O. Widder)
    - Boyd, Thomas Henry
    - Boye
    - Boye Habenicht (Otto H. and George)
    - Bradley Rulofson (Henry W. and William Henry)--Cabinet Cards--#1,2,3,4
    - Bradley Rulofson (Henry W. and William Henry)--Cartes de visite--#1,2
    - Bradley Rulofson (Henry W. and William Henry)--Miscellaneous
    - Brodeck Co. (Henry H. Brodeck)
    - Brown, Thomas A.
    - Brown Otto (Richard Otto)
    - Brunner-Bach
    - Burnett, Franklin W.
    - Burnett Slattery (Franklin W. Burnett, Michael E. Slattery and Thomas Slattery)
    - Bush
    - Bushnell, Frederick H.--#1,2
    - Chalmers Wolf (James C. and Samuel A.)
    - City Mart Photographic Gallery
    - Cobb, David
    - Collins, Isabel Porter (See: Restricted Materials-- Collins, Isabel Porter)
    - Cook, Walter H.
    - Cornell, R.H.
    - Cosmopolitan Art Photographic Co.
    - Cramer, Charles L.
    - Crane
    - Cunningham, Imogen (See: Restricted Materials--Cunningham, Imogen)
    - Dames Butler (William W. and T.A.)
    - Dames Hayes (William W. and Henry C.)
    - Dames Williams (William W. Dames)
    - D.B. Taylor Co. (D.B. Taylor)
    - Dorr, James
    - Dorr Maxwell (James Dorr)
    - Dowe, Arthur W.
    - Dyer, William Denny
    - Edouart, Alexander
    - Edouart Cobb (Alexander and David)--Cabinet Cards
    - Edouart Cobb (Alexander and David)--Cartes de visite
    - Edwards
    - Ehmann, Charles E.
    - Elite Photographic Studio
    - Etter Studio
    - Eureka Art and Photographic Studio
    - Fiske, George
      - #1,2
      - Yosemite
        - (200-249)--Winter Views
        - (250-300)--Summer Views
        - (300-320)--Summer Views
        - (321-350)--Summer Views
        - (351-400)--Summer Views
        - (401-499)--Summer Views
        - (500-599)--Summer Views
        - (No number available)
      - (Suspected Fiskes-More Research Needed)
      - Miscellaneous
    - Flaglor, Amasa P.
    - Ford, Jones
    - Foss, Oscar
    - Fowzer
    - Fredericks
    - Fuller, William H.
    - Fullerton Photo Co. (Samuel J. Fullerton)
    - Godeus, John David
    - Goldsmith, Hugo B.
    - Habenicht
    - Halsey Scripture (John Calvin Scripture)
    - Hamilton, C.F.
    - Hamilton Kellogg (Charles F. and Andrew J.)
    - Hamilton Shew
    - Hamilton Tidball
    - Haussler, Frederick O.
    - Hay
    - Higgins, Thomas J.
    - Hirsh, Hy
    - Holler, Joseph
    - Houseworth, Thomas
    - Howland, Benjamin F.
    - Howland Lonergan
    - Hucks, J. George
    - I.W. Taber Co. (Isaiah West Taber and Thomas Henry Boyd, Yosemite Art Gallery)
    - Imperial Gallery
    - Jackson, J.
    - Jackson, W.F.
    - Johnson, A.P.
    - Johnson, Charles Wallace Jacob
    - Johnson, George Howard
    - Jones Lotz (Thomas H. and Paul)
    - Jones, Robertson Calverley (Thomas H. Jones, Thomas Calverley)
    - Jones, Robinson Co.(Thomas H. Jones and G.M. Robinson)
    - Jones, Rulofson Co.(Thomas H. and William Henry)
    - Keil, Edward A.
    - King Bailey
    - Kingsley, John L.
    - Knight, George H.
    - Lainer, Charles
      - Cabinet Cards
      - Cartes de visite
    - Lange, Oscar V. (See: Restricted Materials--Lange, Oscar V.)
    - Lawrence Houseworth (George S. and Thomas)
    - Marceau, Theodore C.
      - Cabinet Cards
      - Large Photos
    - Marden Brodeck (Robert A. Marden)
    - Marden's National Art Gallery (Robert A. Marden)
    - Marston, Charles A.
    - Marston Cuddeback (Charles A. Marston)
    - Marston, Cuddeback Shew (Charles A. Marston, Jacob Shew)
    - Marston Mains (Charles A. and James Riley)
    - Matson, Frances L.
    - Mattley
    - Morse, George Daniels
      - Cabinet Cards--#1,2,3,4,5
      - Cartes de visite--#1,2
    - Motoyoshi
    - Moulin, Gabriel
    - Muybridge, Eadweard J. (See: Restricted Materials-- Muybridge, Eadweard J. )
    - Myers, Charles A.
    - Nahl Brothers (Charles Christian and Hugo Wilhelm Arthur)
    - Nahl Bros. Dickman (Charles Christian Nahl, Hugo Wilhelm Nahl, and William Dickman)
    - Nast
    - New York Gallery
    - Norton, William S.
    - Olsen, H.
    - Opposition Photographic Gallery
    - Payne Monmonier
    - Perkins
    - Perkins Foss (Alfred Judkins and Oscar)
    - Peters, John Henry
      - Cabinet Cards
      - Cartes de visite
    - Pickett Green
    - Pilliner, William H.
    - Priest, Charles F.
    - Rasmussen
    - Richardson, Leonard
    - Rieman, George B.
    - Rieman Co.
    - Rieman Pray (George B. and Fred H.)
    - Rieman Tuttle (Yosemite Art Gallery)
    - Runnels Stateler (Benjamin F. and John)
    - Savoy Studio
    - Schneider, Max
    - Schoene, Herman
    - Selleck, Silas
    - Sewell, Daniel
    - Sherriff, John A.
    - Shew, Jacob
    - Shew, Marston, Cuddeback
    - Shew, William J.
      - Cabinet Cards
      - Cartes de visite--#1,2,3
    - Sierra
    - Silva, Joseph T.
    - Smith, H. Pierre
    - Starkweather, Joseph B.
    - Sunbeam Gallery
    - Swasey, Fred P.
    - Taber, Isaiah West--#1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12,13
    - T.H. Jones Co. (Thomas H. Jones)
    - Thors (Louis, Katherine, or Gertrude M.)
      - Cabinet Cards--#1,2
      - Cartes de visite
    - Tibbitts, H.C. (Howard Clinton)
    - Todd, John A.
    - Tollman
    - Tonkin, Herbert
    - Treat, Archibald Jennings
    - Turrill Miller--#1,2
    - Tuttle Co.
    - Tuttle Johnson (William Nutting Tuttle)
    - Vaughan, Hector W.--Cabinet Cards
      - Cabinet Cards
      - Cartes de visite
    - Vaughan Fraser
    - Vaughan Keith (Hector M. Vaughan)
    - Vaughan Tidball (Hector W. and Alexander Scott)
    - Vaughan's First Premium Photographic Gallery
    - W.I. Williams Co. (W.I. Williams and W.G. Gregory)
    - W. Monahan Co. (William Monahan, City Mart Photographic Gallery)
    - Walton
    - Waters, Raper James
    - Weed, Charles Leander (see also: Cased Objects--Daguerreotypes)
    - Weyler, E.
    - Whigham, Richard P.
    - White, George R.
    - Williams, Edward A.